newt.org 2010-12-29

# Privacy Policy | Newt.org

**Privacy Policy**

Newt.org is committed to safeguarding your privacy online. To understand how your personal information will be treated please read the following policy. This policy may change from time to time so please check back periodically.  
This policy will let you know:

1\. What personally identifiable information is collected from you;  
2\. What cookies are and how they are used;  
3\. How your information is used;  
4\. Who is collecting your information;  
5\. With whom your information may be shared;  
6\. How you can access, update or delete your information;  
7\. The kind of security precautions that are in place to protect the loss, misuse, or alteration of your information;  
8\. How newt.org protects children's privacy; and  
9\. What else you should know about your online privacy.

**1\. What personally identifiable information does newt.org collect from me?  
** Newt.org collects the information you give when you register to get updates from newt.org. During registration, newt.org asks for your name, email address, and zip code.  You also have the option of giving Newt.org your mailing address, phone number, fax, sometimes your occupation, and personal interests.

In addition to registration we may ask you for personal information at other times, including (but not limited to) when you participate in a special project or event enter sponsored by newt.org. If you contact newt.org we may keep a record of that correspondence. Wherever newt.org collects personal information we make an effort to include a link to this Privacy Policy on that page.

**2\. What are cookies and how does newt.org use them?  
** As part of offering and providing customizable and personalized services, newt.org uses cookies to store some information about you. A cookie is a small amount of data that is sent to your browser from a web server and stored on your computer's hard drive. (See "What are my choices regarding collection, use and distribution of my information?" for more information on cookies.)

**3\. How does newt.org use my information?  
** Newt.org's primary goal in collecting personal information is to provide you, the user, with a updates that you are interested in, like what Newt is doing, books that he has reviewed, speeches, opinion columns, TV and radio appearances, or other projects.

You can opt out of receiving emails by clicking the “unsubscribe” link at the bottom of an email.

**4\. Who is collecting information?  
** When you are on newt.org and are asked for personal information, you are sharing that information with newt.org alone, unless it is specifically stated otherwise. 

In particular, since Newt's free weekly newsletter is distributed by HumanEvents.com, signing up at Newt.org will automatically enroll you to receive Newt's newsletter from HumanEvents.com.  Signing up at Newt.org will not enroll you in any other of HumanEvents.com's newsletters.

Please be aware that newt.org Internet access partners, advertisers, and web sites that have links on our site may collect personally identifiable information about you. The information practices of those Internet access partners, advertisers, and web sites linked to newt.org are not covered by this privacy statement.

**5\. With whom does newt.org share my information?  
** As a general rule, newt.org will not disclose any of your personally identifiable information except when we have your permission or under special circumstances, such as when we believe in good faith that the law requires it or under the circumstances described below.

Business Partners & Sponsors : newt.org may disclose your personal information to business partners or sponsors, but this is specifically described to you prior to data collection or prior to transferring the data.

Many promotions offer opportunities to request additional information from sponsors. By requesting more information, you give newt.org permission to transfer your personal information to the sponsor so they can fulfill your request. In many instances, only your email address will be shared. If more information will be shared with the sponsor, you will be notified prior to the transfer.

Newt.org partners with HumanEvents.com to distribute Newt’s free weekly newsletter.  We may from time to time also work with HumanEvents.com to send you special offers and advertisements for products or services offered by third parties. We will not disclose any of your personal information to such third parties when we do this.  Sending you offers from our sponsors is one of the ways we financially sustain Newt.org’s operations so we can continue to provide you with Newt’s latest analysis and news.

Other: newt.org may also disclose account information in special cases when we have reason to believe that disclosing this information is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be causing injury to or interference with (either intentionally or unintentionally) newt.org's rights or property, other newt.org users, or anyone else that could be harmed by such activities. Newt.org may disclose or access account information when we believe in good faith that the law requires it.

**6\. How you can access, update or delete your information?  
** You have choices with respect to cookies. By modifying your browser preferences, you have the choice to accept all cookies, to be notified when a cookie is set, or to reject all cookies. If you choose to reject all cookies you will be unable to use those newt.org services that require registration in order to participate. You can still use newt.org, read but not post even if you do not accept cookies.

Newt.org does not share user information with anyone. From time to time Newt.org or our partners at HumanEvents.com may send you a message about third party events or promotions and it will be up to you to share your information with that party, but newt.org will not share that information with any third party.

**7\. What is newt.org's policy on allowing me to update, correct, or delete my personally identifiable information?  
** You may change or request that newt.org delete you information at anytime by submitting a change request. You must identify the e-mail address that you are receiving our messages from.

**8\. What security precautions are in place to protect the loss, misuse, or alteration of my information?  
** Whenever newt.org handles personal information as described above, regardless of where this occurs, newt.org takes steps to ensure that your information is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet or any wireless network can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your personal information, newt.org cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us or from our online products or services, and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your transmission, we make our best effort to ensure its security on our systems.

**9\. What about children's privacy?  
** Naturally, the safety of children is very important to us. Newt.org recommends that parents review all the sites their children visit to ensure that age appropriate content.

Newt.org is a general audience web site that complies with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act.

Under the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act, no web site operator is permitted to require a child under the age of 13 to disclose more information than is reasonably necessary to participate in an activity as a condition of participation. Newt.org abides by this requirement.

**10\. What else should I know about my privacy?  
** Please keep in mind that whenever you voluntarily disclose personal information online - for example on message boards, through email, or in chat areas - that information can be collected and used by others. In short, if you post personal information online that is accessible to the public, you may receive unsolicited messages from other parties in return.

Ultimately, you are solely responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your passwords and/or any account information. Please be careful and responsible whenever you're online.
